Inventory of the Robert F. Wheeler Papers, 1898-1977
Hoover Institution Archives
- Remainder of reels not indexed/catalogued:
  - 1 reel with notations: BA Koblenz, IISG. (Reel 29)
    - IISG information: a) Soz. Auslander Korrespondenz. Sozialist
    - b) Forum
    - c) Komm. Rundschau
    - d) Parteitag USPD, 1923
    - e) IASP Nachrichten.
  - 1 reel entitled:Strom (Reel 30)
  - 1 reel with positive microfilm from the 1940s with US State Department microcopy memos. reel is about Axis-Afghanistan trade and financial negotiations, 1940-1943. (Reel 31)
    - (White-red box with following typewritten notations:
      - Serial No. 353 Frame No. 202941-203094
      - 351 202342 202603
      - 344 200036-200139
  - 1 reel in white box with orang striping with notation on outside: Verein Arbeiterpresse (Partial), 1927 (Reel 32)
  - I reel in white box with brown carboard taped to the sides entitled: Hoover assorted. (Reel 33)
    - Notations: Scheel--April Streik
    - Bernhard-Revol....
    - Boris Nicolaiv?sky Les Premieres Annees
    - de...Int. 1. Communiste
    - Die Jugend der Revolution
    - some other poorly legible indications.
  - 1 reel in white box with notations: Hoover Institution H21 Author HD4809/V489/1914 (typewritten). Also in marker pen by researcher: Verband Arbeitz.? (Reel 34)
    - Ball-point: Verband Volksgesundheit
    - M. König, Dresden- Kötzschenbroda
    - (p.239-1914AB)
  - 6 reels in blue boxes from the National Archives (One box opened at random contained documentation from the period German language material)., 1940 1945. (Reel 35-40)
  - 1 container roll size for 36 exposures with notation "Potsdam 05750. R. Wheeler." (Reel 41)
  - 3 small folders for negative film containing strips of microfilm one with inscription Thuringen. Rote Chronik, 1931 Zeitz,-Weissenfels-Naumberg. The two other folders are empty. (Reel 47)
  - One reel with 20 frames of General records of the Dept. of State re: List of Papers Bolshevik propaganda.-----US., (dated Oct. 15, 1669) 1919-1920-1921. (Reel 42)
  - One reel from Deutsches Zentralarchiv, Merseburg, D.D.R. (Reel 43)
  - One reel from SA, Leipzig (Reel 44)
  - One reel from SA, Dresden (Reel 45)
  - One reel from IML (Reel 46)
- Robert Wheeler collection
  - Reichsministerium des Inneren has been put on three separate reels: (Reel 43)
    - Misc. plitical, police and military reports, ca. 1920 (Reel #43:)
    - Misc. political, police and military reports including correspondence of military leadership KPD Halle during March 1921 uprising., ca. 1918-1921 (Reel #43a:)
    - Misc. documents from, 1920's - 1030's. (Reel #43b:)
- Sound recordings, 11 sound cassettes (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet)
  - Haupt / Wheeler
    Access
    Use copy reference number: 79001_a_0010467
  - I and II
    Use copy reference number: 79001_a_0010457
  - IV
    Use copy reference number: 79001_a_0010451
  - Labor history lecture
    Use copy reference number: 79001_a_0010452
  - Morning discussion
    Use copy reference number: 79001_a_0010447
  - Santa Barbara
    Use copy reference number: 79001_a_0010461
  - Sender
    Use copy reference number: 79001_a_0010466
  - Spanish Civil War
    Use copy reference number: 79001_a_0010462
  - Thirty Years War lecture
    Use copy reference number: 79001_a_0010448